indigovolunteers.org 2018-09-30

# Privacy Policy |

## **Privacy Policy  **

It is our policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website. This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

The processing of your personal data is carried out by or on behalf of indiGO Volunteers (registered charity number 1158459). This policy may change from time to time, so please visit this page periodically to make sure you’re up to date.

**Who are we?**

indiGO Volunteers work with courageous humanitarian projects that serve people in impoverished communities and refugee camps. We help them get the brilliant volunteers they need to achieve their bold ambitions. We do not charge a penny to anyone for doing this we’re the world’s first global totally fee-free volunteering organisation

**How can you contact us?**

If you have any questions regarding this policy or our processing of your personal information, please get in touch at info@indigovolunteers.org, and we will get back to you as soon as possible.

**How do we collect your information?**

We may collect information about you whenever you directly interact with us. For example, when you: make a donation; when you register to volunteer; when you use our website.

**What type of information is collected from you?**

The information we collect from you may include:

  * Your name
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number
  * Your emergency contact
  * Your taxpayer status for claiming Gift Aid
  * Your date of birth
  * Your gender
  * Your volunteer experience / profession

We do not use cookies to collect this type of information. All online financial transactions will be encrypted using TLS (Transport Layer Security).

**How is your information used?**

We may use your information to:

  * Process a donation that you have made
  * Provide you with information about our work or our activities
  * Carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into by you and us
  * Process volunteer registration
  * Seek your views or comments on the services we provide;
  * Notify you of changes to our services
  * Analyse and improve the content and operation of our website
  * Disclose or otherwise use your information where we are required by law.

In particular, we may contact you for marketing purposes by email if you have agreed to be contacted in this manner. We provide information about how you can change your marketing preferences in our communications.

**How do we store your information?**

We take appropriate physical, electronic and managerial measures to ensure that we keep your information secure, accurate and up to date. We use Sales force system to collect and store your information.

Sales Force system is a Customer relationship management system (CRM system).  
Sales Force allows us to collect, log, manage and analyse all ‘customer’ activity in one place with a web-based CRM software.

We collect customer / volunteer information on an application form through our website pages of which is then transferred to the Sales Force system.

We also use a web-based project management application called Trello to store and manage customer / volunteer data. The customer / volunteer information is collected from a form through our website and then transferred to the Trello system.

The storing and collection of the customer / volunteer data is depended on the project in which they (the customer / volunteer) apply for.

Although we use appropriate security measures once we have received your personal information, the transmission of information over the internet is never completely secure. We do our best to protect personal information, but we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted to our website, so any transmission is at the user’s own risk. However, any payment card details (such as credit or debit cards) we receive on our website are passed securely to our payment processing provider according to the Payment Card Industry Security Standards.

**How long will we keep your information?**

We will keep your personal information as long as it is reasonable and necessary.  Generally we will keep your financial information for as long as the law requires which may be up to 6 years.

**Your choices**

You have a choice about whether or not you receive communications from us. If you do not want to receive direct marketing communications from us about the vital work we do to link volunteers to projects that help refugees and displaced people, then you can manage the communications you wish to receive.  You can do this by ticking the relevant boxes situated on the application and/or enquiry forms where we collect your information or by contacting us by email at info@indigovolunteers.org to unsubscribe to future communications.

We will not contact you for marketing purposes by email, phone or text message unless you have given your prior consent. We will not contact you for marketing purposes by post if you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted. You can change your marketing preferences at any time by contacting us by email: info@indigovolunteers.org

**What are your rights?**

You have right to access your personal information which is processed by indiGO Volunteers. You also have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data and/or that your personal data is deleted.  If you can show us that the information we have about you is incorrect, you can request that this personal data is updated. You can object to your personal data being processed by us if you feel that it isn’t in indiGO Volunteers legitimate interest to process your personal data.  If you would like to exercise any of your rights please contact us at info@indigovolunteers.org.

**Who has access to your information?**

We will not sell or rent your information to third parties.

We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.

indiGO Volunteers will share your information with associations we work in partnership with (for example, when you wish to volunteer and so are placed with a certain project). We will not do this without your consent. In some cases, they will be acting as a data controller of your information and therefore we advise you to read their Privacy Policy.

**Links to other websites and organisations**

Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the Privacy Policies on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the Privacy Policies and practices of other sites even if you access those using links from our website.

**16 or Under**

We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian’s permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information. All the projects we support do not take volunteers of 16 years and under therefore this information will be deleted unless they consent for indiGO to send them mailers.

**Why are we allowed to process your personal information?**

Our Privacy Policy take into account several laws, including:

– the Data Protection Act 1998, which will be replaced by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 on the 25 May 2018

– the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

Generally, our processing of your personal information as described in this policy is allowed by these laws in order for us to provide our services to you, to comply with our statutory obligations, for our legitimate interests or the interests of a third party, or with your consent. 

**Your credit or debit card information**

If you use your credit or debit card to donate to us, buy something or make a booking online, we pass your card details securely to our payment processing partner as part of the payment process. We do this in accordance with the Payment Card Industry Security Standard [(PDF download)](https://helprefugees.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PCI-DSS.pdf), and don’t store the details on our website or databases.

**Emails**

Emails are not always secure, and they may be intercepted or changed after they have been sent. indiGO Volunteers does not accept liability if this happens. The contents of emails reflect their author’s views and not necessarily those of indiGO Volunteers.

Please **do not**  send indiGO Volunteers any financial data through email.

**Making a complaint**

If you would like to make a complaint about how we have handled your personal data please contact us at [info@indigovolunteers.org](mailto:info@indigovolunteers.org). You can also contact the ICO at the following address:

Information Commissioner’s Office

Wycliffe House

Water Lane 

Wilmslow

Cheshire

SK9 5AF

**Review of this Policy**

We regularly review and update our Privacy Policy. This policy was last updated in May 2018.
